Siddharth Choudhary

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/siddharth-choudhary-440102b8/ Email: sidchoudhary.in@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/SiddharthChoudhary Phone: +1 551-482-8414

Summary

Software Engineer with 4+ years of professional experience in commercial application development. Leading projects, engaging in customer meetings by accommodating the incoming requests; Designing system architectures, contributing to and building CI/CD pipelines for the seamless integration of deployments; Qualifications also include completion of Masters in Computer Science.

Technical Skills (Computer Science)

Programming/Scripting Languages: Python, React, Typescript, Kotlin, Swift, JS (ES6+), Java, Nodejs, Spring Boot, PHP, Angular, C **Devops related tools:** AWS Stack, CI/CD, Jenkins, Git, Docker, Kubernetes, GCP, Firebase

Frameworks: Express.js, React-Native, React-Redux, Redis, MongoDB, Pytest, Jest, Mocha, GraphQL, Java Hibernate, Laravel, VueJs, Android, MySQL, Python-Pandas, Python-Numpy

Education

Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, NJ

Aug 2018 - May 2020

Master of Science in Computer Science (GPA- 3.8/4.0)

Coursework: Advanced Programming in the Unix Env., Distributed Systems, Advanced Web Programming, Advanced Algorithms.

RTU, Rajasthan, INDIA

Aug 2013 - May 2017

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology

Coursework: Networking, Principles of Programming Language, Data Structures & Algorithms, Computer Networks

Experience

Software Developer II, Oracle Cloud Infrastructure

Jan 2022 - Present

- Deploying IaC using Terraform in OCI to increase the migration speed from an old generation infrastructure.
- Collaborated with other OCI teams, as a cross-team effort, to build and deploy Devops portal using React-js, Node-js.
- Providing on-call support, maintaining the fault tolerance and scaling out of our core features to the distributed servers within OCI.

Software Engineer, Nextiles

Jan 2021 - Jan 2022

(Technical Skills: SwiftUI-Swift, Kotlin, Jenkins, Python, Frameworks, Firebase, AWS DDB, S3, Cloud Stack)

- Built cloud solutions and CI/CD pipelines for the entire backend in AWS environment (S3, DDB, Codepipeline).
- Incorporated customer needs, engaged in client meetings and worked closely with their development teams to help with SDK integration..

Software Development Engineer, Amazon(Amazon Web Services)

Jul 2020 - Dec 2020

(Technical Skills: Pytest, Python, AWS CodeBuild, JAVA-Spring, AWS Frameworks, Ruby, CI/CD deployments)

- Integrated with an internal team at AWS to provide tagging feature to power the APIs for our project layers
- Built an infrastructure for product's API layers, control flow layers, and end to end integration tests for the service

Associate Application Developer, ADP

Feb 2020 - Jul 2020

(Technical Skills: Typescript, MongoDb, Express.js, ES6, React-redux, GraphQL)

- Powered CEH product by building modules supporting automation testing team using Expressjs/GraphQL backend & React front-end
- Built UI modules, utilizing MongoDB database and contributed to microservices based architecture

Full Stack Developer, Samy Web Technologies

Jan 2018 - Jun 2018

(Technical Skills: Laravel, Paypal Integration, Google Third Party APIs, ElasticSearch, REST APIs, Semantic UI)

- Created the Checkout flow, Add to cart, Payment modules (using Paypal integration) for the Scubaya project
- Reduced the extra consuming time as compared to a regular search by implementing an optimized indexing search.

Full Stack Developer, ReadyBytes Software Labs

Jan 2017 - Dec 2017

(Technical Skills: Java, Spring Boot, Jquery, HTML5 & CSS, SQL, Php, Redis, Node.js)

- Contributed and maintained CMS software solutions to handle the back end of an e-service platform.
- Introduced new cloud services for more user interaction which increased the overall sales by nearly 30%.

Internships

Global Product and Technology Intern (Devops Team), ADP

May 2019 - Aug 2019

• Automated several Jenkins jobs by creating python modules for Devops team to generate health checks for running docker containers.